你正被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people,
像你一样的普通人
people like you,
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第17集
Person of Interest S01E17 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-
听说没  莫雷蒂要出狱了
Did you hear? Moretti's getting out of the slammer.
莫雷蒂  你认为以利亚知道吗
Moretti? Do you think Elias knows?
开什么玩笑  我以为这就是以利亚安排的
Kidding me? I think Elias arranged it.
他想要莫雷蒂出来
Wants him out in the open.
你从哪儿冒出来的
Where the hell did you come from?
我想散散步
Felt like a walk.
从曼哈顿散步出来80公里?
50 miles from Manhattan?
开门
Open the gate.
别告诉我你是为了莫雷蒂而来
Don't tell me you're here for Moretti.
你怎么知道他要被释放了
How did you know he was being released?
早该猜到了
Should have guessed.
你一出现
Whenever you show up,
麻烦也就不远了
trouble's right around the corner.
你有什么计划  卡特
What's your plan, Carter?
我可以给莫雷蒂提供保护
I got authority to offer Moretti protection.
作为交换  他要告诉我们
In exchange, he tells us
如何抓到纽约的头号公敌
how to get New York's public enemy number one.
他的亲生儿子
His own son.
他的亲儿子以利亚
His own son Elias.
你在吗  芬奇
You there, Finch?
马上要走  看到莫雷蒂没有
Not for long. Have you seen Moretti?
他正开始享受自由的空气
Enjoying his first breath of freedom.
-你要出去吗  -刚得到一个号码
- You going somewhere? - Got another number
是社会保障局两个月前发放的
issued by the Social Security Administration two months ago
给了一个叫莉拉・史密斯的女人
to a woman named Leila Smith.
要么是新入籍的公民  要么是身份诈欺
Either a new citizen or a case of identity fraud.
我只能找到一个工作地址
All I could find was a work address.
我们正在忙莫雷蒂的事  芬奇
We're working Moretti's number, Finch.
你得待在总部
I need you at HQ.
号码不等人  里瑟先生
The numbers don't wait in line, Mr. Reese.
保持联系
Be in touch.
卡特  纽约警察  记得我吗
Carter, NYPD. Remember me?
条子长得都一个样
Cops all look the same.
你清楚以利亚正在找你
You know Elias is looking for you.
-我没见着他  -暂时而已
- I don't see him. - Not yet.
我可以给你安排个安全的地方
But I could put you somewhere safe,
保你活下去
try to keep you alive.
现在我记起你了
Now I remember you now.
你是以利亚要杀的人
You're the one Elias wanted to kill.
那名我行我素的警察
The cop who's on her own.
看来世道没怎么变啊
Looks like nothing's changed.
你不在这里工作  莉拉
You don't work here, Leila.
你是这里的病人
You're a patient.
知道他要去哪儿么
Any idea where he's going?
他以前在这里有一处房产
He used to own a house out here.
你好  我是提尔曼医生  找莉拉・史密斯
Hello, I'm Dr. Tillman, here to see Leila Smith.
阿戴里安医生让我检查她支气管炎的状况
Dr. Adalian asked me to check the status of her bronchitis.
她现在基本痊愈了
She's pretty well over that by now.
尽管如此  你有她的表格么
Nonetheless. Do you have her chart for me?
她在这儿
Here she is.
我们的小天使
Our own little angel.
没写她的父母是谁
No parents listed.
莉拉是被放在安全岛的弃婴
Oh, Leila's a safe-haven baby.
阿戴里安医生在诊所外面发现的她
Dr. Adalian himself found her outside the clinic.
谁给她申请的社保号
So who applied for her social security number?
是我
That was me.
我希望国家知道莉拉是谁
I wanted to be sure the state knew who Leila was,
即使她父母完全不在乎
even if her own parents didn't care.
通常情况下她应该已经被送养了
Normally she'd be given up for adoption by now,
但她有支气管炎之类的疾病
but she had medical issues like her bronchitis.
她会很快找到一个家的
She'll find a home soon.
谢谢你  护士
Thank you, nurse.
你好  莉拉
Hello, Leila.
这世界上会有谁居然想伤害你
Now who in the world would want to hurt you?
我们来找莉拉・史密斯
We're here for Leila Smith.
要把她转到另一家诊所
Here to transfer her to another clinic.
里瑟先生  我这里有情况
Mr. Reese, I think I have a situation.
我也是  等下打给你
Me too. I have to get back to you.
这边走
This way.
像是出了事故
Looks like an accident.
绕开它们
Go around them.
求你了  能帮帮我们吗
Please, can you help us?
继续开
Keep going.
-出来  -警察  放下武器
- Get out! - Police! Drop your weon.
快  我们走
Come on, let's go.
我听说了事情的经过
I heard what happened.
你应该庆幸她在场  莫雷蒂先生
You're very lucky she was there, Mr. Moretti.
是啊  你是谁
Yeah. Who are you?
舍曼斯基警探
Detective Szymanski.
又一个警察
Another cop.
我必须待在这里吗
Do I have to stay here?
你是自由身  吉亚尼
You're a free man, Gianni.
你随时可以出去吃子弹
You can walk out of here and into a bullet anytime,
或者留下来帮我们抓住以利亚
or you can stay and help us get Elias before he gets you.
一个东躲西藏的黑手党老头子
A mafia don in hiding.
你打算向上级汇报吗
You plan on clearing this with your bosses?
已经汇报过了
It's already cleared.
以利亚没有掌控我们整个部门
Elias doesn't own the whole department--
目前还没
Not yet.
还有几个像舍曼斯基这样的好警察
Still a few good cops like Szymanski in there,
想要抓住以利亚
who want Elias taken down
而莫雷蒂就是最好的途径
and think Moretti is the best way to do it.
不管怎样
Anyway...
多谢你了
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
别惹麻烦
Stay out of trouble.
芬奇  那边怎么样
Hey, Finch. How's it going?
就那样
It's going.
莫雷蒂情况如何
What about Moretti?
以利亚给他准备了一个出狱派对
Elias had a getting-out-of-jail party planned.
我们捣毁了它
We crashed it.
另一个号码情况如何  芬奇
What happened with the other number, Finch?
舌头打结了
Cat got your tongue?
我可能行事有点草率了
I'm afraid I may have done something rather rash.
什么叫草率了
What do you mean by "Rash"?
那是你的领带吗  芬奇
Is this one of your ties, Finch?
你还是给她点吃的  而不是你穿过的衣服
I hope you gave her some food and not just your hand-me-downs.
她喜欢鸡肉和梅干
Chicken and prunes is her favorite.
听着  有点恶心
Sounds, disgusting.
但怎么会有人想要杀她
But why on earth would anyone want to kill her?
我倒没觉得有人想要杀她
Somehow I don't see anyone planning a murder here.
我推测  如果他们成功绑架了她
My guess is that, if they were successful in kidnapping her,
会把她偷渡出国
they'd smuggle her out of the country
把她扔进孤儿院
and dump her in an orphanage.
扔到某个有很多小孩
Somewhere where babies are plentiful
却又缺乏出生记录的地方
and birth records aren't.
但是他们为什么想摆脱掉她
But why do they want to get rid of her?
她或许是一桩私情的证据
She might be evidence of an affair,
或者阻碍了某人
or she might be an obstacle to someone
获得巨额遗产
getting a big, fat legacy.
但到底是谁  我还没有头绪
As for who they are, I have no idea.
不过由于她让我一晚没睡
But since she kept me up all night,
我查了诊所的财务
I looked into the clinic's finances.
他们收到一份大礼
They received a big gift.
莉拉出生前5万美金
$50,000 just about the time Leila was born
此后每月都有1万美金
and $10,000 every month since then.
捐赠者是谁
Who's the donor?
匿名
Anonymous.
我以国税局的名义发了一份措辞严厉的邮件
I sent the clinic a sternly worded email from the IRS
要求查看捐赠者的税收账号
demanding the donor's tax ID number
威胁他们如果不尽快答复
and threatening to review their charitable status
就要审查他们的慈善运营资格  等着瞧吧
if they didn't answer quickly. We'll see how that works.
纽约警局
儿童绑架
莉拉・史密斯
安珀警报
Amber Alert.
北美发生儿童绑架案时发布的警戒告知
婴儿昨晚于圣雷蒙德的诊所被绑架
"Baby kidnapped from St. Raymond's clinic last night.
嫌犯男子身材矮个  发色灰褐
Suspect is a short man with mousy hair
带厚框眼镜
and thick glasses."
倒不算恭维你  芬奇  不过你比画像好看
It's not very flattering, Finch, but better than the picture
难怪他们靠这个从来抓不到人
It's no wonder they never catch anybody with these things.
你觉得卡特能帮我们打探警方的调查吗
You think Carter can piggyback the police investigation?
我去问她
I'll ask her.
你可以好好陪陪莉拉
You can spend some quality time with Leila.
警探
Detective.
莫雷蒂先生告诉你以利亚的情况了吗
Has Mr. Moretti given you anything on Elias?
还没有  不过  我们还在努力
Not yet, but, um, we're working on him.
你买婴儿用品干什么
Who you buying that stuff for?
我想和你谈的就是这个
That's why I wanted to talk to you.
一个婴儿昨晚在华盛顿高地一个诊所失踪了
A baby went missing from a clinic in Washington Heights last night.
失踪  是被偷了
Missing? It was stolen...
被一个长得奇形怪状的
It was stolen by some weird-looki--
不是吧
No.
你不是吧
You didn't.
她正处在被绑架的极度危险中
She was in imminent danger of kidnap.
所以你就绑架了她吗
So you kidnapped her?
你知道你被安珀警报通缉了吧
You know there's an Amber Alert out on you.
是的  所以我们需要你的帮助
Yes, and that's why we need your help.
帮助  我该逮捕你
Help? I should arrest you.
那孩子现在在哪里
Where's the baby anyway?
莉拉很安全  她和约翰在一起
Leila's safe. She's with John.
约翰  约翰  你居然放心他带孩子
John? John? You trust him with a baby?
我知道这样不太好
I realize it's not ideal.
所以我们越快解决问题越好
So the sooner we can resolve this, the better.
你还要我做些什么
What do you want me to do?
除了不逮捕你以外
Apart from not arresting you.
去诊所
Go to the clinic.
看看能不能找到莉拉父母的信息
See what you can find out about Leila's parents.
我听说她是被放在安全岛的弃婴
I heard she was a safe-haven baby.
诊所是不会有她父母的信息的
Clinic's not going to have that information.
我想他们比声称的知道得多
I think they know more than they claim.
去找艾博特护士谈谈
Talk to a nurse Abbot.
她似乎特别喜欢莉拉
She seemed especially fond of Leila.
恭喜
Congratulations.
是第一个孩子吗
Is it your first?
这就是你青春驻颜的秘诀吗
That how you keep your boyish figure?
有种咬我
Bite me.
听说了吗  吉亚尼・莫雷蒂昨天出狱后
Did you hear Gianni Moretti got out of prison yesterday
人间蒸发了
then vanished?
国民警卫队找到了五具混混的尸体
All state police found was five dead goombas.
暴徒自相残杀  悲剧啊
Mobsters killing each other-- How tragic.
不过那儿不止有暴徒
Except it wasn't just mobsters.
你的搭档也在
Your partner was there too.
卡特吗
Carter?
似乎她和几个愣头青
Looks like she and a couple of cowboys
去执行某个未记录在案的破任务了
got some kind of rinky-dink off-book operation.
他们把莫雷蒂藏起来了
They've hidden Moretti.
我们要知道他藏哪儿了
We want to find out where.
HR找不到他
HR can't find out?
还以为你们的爪牙遍布各处呢
Thought you guys had your fingers in all the pies.
你就是其中一个  弗斯科
You are one of the pies, Fusco.
找出她把莫雷蒂藏哪儿了
Find out where she's got Moretti stashed.
就跟我和其他警探说的一样
Like I told the other detectives,
我们没有莉拉的父母的信息
we don't know about the parents.
莉拉被遗弃在诊所外面
Leila was just left outside the clinic.
她身上有什么东西吗
Was there anything found on Leila?
我是阿戴里安医生  你是哪位
I'm Dr. Adalian. Who are you?
-卡特警探  特殊受害者小组的  -警探
- Detective Carter, SVU. - Detective.
我想艾博特护士已经解释过了
As I'm sure nurse Abbot explained,
我们并不知道莉拉的父母是谁
we don't know where Leila came from.
你们一定留下了什么东西
You must have kept something.
比如  她的衣服  或是包着她的毯子
Like, what about her clothes, her blankets?
没有  安全岛条律的目的是保护新生儿
No. The, Safe-haven Law was designed to protect newborns
而不是指控父母
not prosecute their parents.
我们的工作不是抓人
It's not our job to hunt people down.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
等一下
Excuse me.
我关心的只是莉拉
All I care about is Leila.
如果你想起了什么  打给我
If you can think of anything, call me.
拜托了
Please.
这片粘在这里  那片粘在那里  看到没
This flap here, that flap there, see?
干净整洁多简单
Neat and simple.
你在麻省理工的书果然没白念
I see your time at MIT wasn't wasted.
太好菜了  诊所的会计师发邮件来了
Excellent. The accountants at the clinic have coughed up
是他们捐献人的税号
the tax ID numbers of their donor.
没什么比国税局更可怕了
Nothing like a fear of the IRS to produce results.
税号属于彼得罗辛建筑公司
Tax ID belongs to Petrosian Construction.
公司所有人是
Company owned by...
阿德南・彼得罗辛
Adnan Petrosian.
我们只要扒扒大众媒体的
And if we dive into that swamp of indiscretion
八卦资讯
known as social media,
就会发现
we will learn that...
阿德南・彼得罗辛和妻子尼可娜
Adnan Petrosian has been married to Nicola
已结婚二十多年
for more than 20 years.
育有一子布兰得利
They have one son Bradley,
正在攻读纽约大学金融硕士学位
who's taking a master's in finance at NYU.
这个巴巴
Dadda?
还是这个巴巴
Or dadda?
严肃点  里瑟先生
Be serious, Mr. Reese.
你去接近他们一家
I need you to get close to this family.
芬奇
Hey, Finch.
监视已经搞定  正在装监听
Got eyes on the Petrosians, getting ears.
他们是真正的富人  芬奇
These guys have serious money, Finch.
你们的一家俱乐部可能是同一家
You probably go to the same country club.
即使如此
Be that as it may,
他们看起来像是丢了宝宝的样子吗
do they seem like a family that's lost a baby?
你搞臭了家族的名誉
Behavior has damaged this family's good name,
我已经花了那么多钱帮你摆脱麻烦了
and I've already spent a fortune getting you out of trouble.
很抱歉让你脸上无光了  爸爸
Oh, I'm so sorry I embarrassed you, dad.
布兰得利  我想知道  就这一个
Bradley, I want to know, is this it,
还是有别的麻烦在等着
or are there more unpleasant surprises?
全都搞定了  好吗
It's been taken care of, okay?
看起来是父母在掩护他们的儿子
Looks like mommy and daddy are covering up for the son.
来点美味的牛奶好不好
How about a delicious bottle?
芬奇  你有在听吗
Finch, are you listening?
真乖
Oh, there you go.
卡特警探的电话
Detective Carter's phone.
请让特殊受害者小组的卡特警探接电话好吗
Can I have Detective Carter, SVU?
卡特是凶案组的亲  不是特殊受害者小组的
Carter works Homicide, sweetheart, not SVU.
我是卡特  有什么能帮到您的吗
This is Carter. How can I help you?
我是玛丽・艾博特
It's Mary Abbot.
刚才那个男的说你是凶案组的
The man on the phone said you worked Homicide.
别听他的  他是新来的
Oh, don't worry about him. He's new here.
有什么能帮到你的吗  玛丽
How could I help you, Mary?
当时莉拉身上的确有东西  一条手链
Leila did have something on her when she arrived--a bracelet
你还保管着吗
Do you still have it?
我给了主任  阿戴里安医生
I gave it to the director, Dr. Adalian.
我问过他  可是他说他不记得了
I asked him, but he said he didn't remember.
是什么样的手链
What did it look like?
是银的
It was silver,
上面有两个缩写  CC
with two initials carved on it. CC.
好的  谢谢你  玛丽
Okay, thank you, Mary.
我到时候再联系你
I'll talk to you soon.
好的  警探
All right, Detective.
找到个在彼得罗辛办公室工作的人缩写叫CC
I've found one CC. working in the Petrosian home,
凯莉・克罗斯威尔
Carrie Crosswell.
但她58了  搞外遇有点偏老
But she's 58-- a little old for a fling.
我正在比对彼得罗辛建筑公司的雇员名单
Now I'm checking employee files at Petrosian Construction.
你黑进了人家公司
You hacked into his company?
"黑进"这词真难听
"Hacked" is such an ugly word.
又找到了两个缩写叫CC的人
And we have two more CCs.
查德・科伦坡  四十岁  电焊工
Chad Colombo, 40, a welder,
不像能生出孩子
unlikely to bear a child.
还有一个克劳迪娅・克鲁兹  二十岁
And Claudia Cruz, 20,
总公司的前台接待
receptionist in the head office.
克劳迪娅・克鲁兹  正在查
Claudia Cruz. Checking.
8个月前她结束了与彼得罗辛的雇佣关系
Employment with Petrosian ended eight months ago,
那会儿正好是她肚子显形的时候
just when her pregnancy would have started to show.
给我地址  我去跟她谈谈
Get me an address. I'll go and talk to her.
谈不了  她死了
No, you won't. She's dead.
一份犯罪现场报告上有她的名字
Name showed up on a crime scene report.
四天前死于公寓火灾
Died in her apartment from a fire four days ago.
法医当意外事故处理的
ME ruled it as an accident.
真可爱  可以跟她打招呼吗
Aw, cute. Can we say Hi?
太萌了
Oh, she's so adorable.
你好啊  小可爱
Hi, honey.
-看她笑的  -谢谢  再见
- Look at that smile. - Thanks. Bye.
你居然随身带着她
You brought her with you?
整个城市的警察都在找她
Every cop in the city is looking for that kid.
我在教她怎么掩护自己
I'm teaching her to go undercover.
她天生就擅长
She's a natural.
她是小天使
She's a little angel.
要是她出了事  约翰  上帝救救我吧
Something happens to her, John, so help me, God--
我们正努力阻止坏事发生
We're trying to stop anything from happening.
我们知道她待在彼得罗辛家族资助的诊所
We know she was in a clinic funded by the Petrosians,
而她妈妈曾经为那个家族工作
and we know her mother worked for the Petrosians.
她生父很可能是彼得罗辛家族成员之一
So it's probable that the father is one of the Petrosians.
但她母亲为什么会死于意外呢
But why does mom end up dead?
或许她之前同意把孩子送去让人领养
Maybe she agreed to give her up for adoption,
却又改变了主意  想要留下孩子
then changed her mind, said she wanted to keep it.
这会使整件事曝光
Well, that would expose the whole thing.
DNA会证明孩子父亲是谁
DNA would prove who the father was.
他得供养这个孩子
He'd have to provide for the baby.
-家族会受损失  -这是动机
- The family would lose out. - It's motive.
做掉母亲
Bump off the mom,
让孩子失踪  问题解决了
make the baby disappear, problem solved.
我们得查查克劳迪娅
We need to find out if Claudia's death
是否真的死于意外
really was an accident.
我已经找出尸检和犯罪现场调查报告
I already pulled the autopsy and crime scene reports.
我会跟一名朋友一起去检查现场
I want to look through them with a mentor of mine.
-他在消防部门工作  -很好
- Works for the Fire Department. - Good.
我去看看克劳迪娅的父母有没有任何线索
I'll see if Claudia's parents know anything.
约翰继续跟踪布兰得利・彼得罗辛
John will follow Bradley Petrosian.
我得先喂饱莉拉
After I've fed Leila.
再见啦
Bye-bye.
克鲁兹夫人  我是卢卡斯・班纳特
Mrs. Cruz. Lucas Bennet.
家庭事务部的
Department of Family Services.
他说是为克劳迪娅的事情而来
He says he's here about Claudia.
请节哀顺变
I'm very sorry for your loss.
您为何而来
Why are you here?
我们接到一个报告...
We had a report, um...
来自克劳迪娅的一位邻居  匿名的
from a neighbor of Claudia's-- an anonymous report--
说她怀孕了
that she was pregnant.
她没有  谁说的
She was not. Tell me who said that.
对不起  克鲁兹先生  这是匿名消息
Please, Mr. Cruz, the source is anonymous.
我们需要进行调查
We have to investigate.
好吧
Okay.
克劳迪娅没有怀孕
Claudia wasn't pregnant.
我是她母亲  我们无话不谈
I'm her mother. We talked about everything.
克劳迪娅什么时候搬进那套公寓的
When did Claudia move into her apartment?
大概是九个月前  怎么了
About nine months ago. Why?
正好那会儿她离开了
About the same time that she stopped working
彼得罗辛建筑公司
at Petrosian Construction?
那段时间你们见过她吗
Did you see her during that period?
有好几个月都没见她了
Not for a few months, no.
她似乎不太愿意我们去看她
She was kind of funny about us coming around.
克劳迪娅是不是有条银手链
Did Claudia have a silver bracelet?
没错  上面有她的首字母
Yes, with her initials on it.
她很小的时候我母亲送给她的
My mother gave it to her when she was a baby.
拜托  有什么就说吧
Please, just tell us.
她真的怀孕了吗  她有孩子了吗
Was she pregnant? Did she have a baby?
我们认为有可能
We believe it's possible.
这孩子在哪儿  我们能见见吗
Then where is it? Can we see it?
我可以居中安排你们相见
I can try to arrange a meeting on neutral ground,
但是这事情得保密
but it would have to be kept confidential.
没问题
Of course.
有其他克劳迪娅的事可以告诉我吗
What else can you tell me about Claudia?
譬如说  她在恋爱吗
Was she in a relationship, for example?
她死前一个月曾经留了些文件在家
She left some papers here about a month before she died.
我们发现了这个
We found this.
我觉得这是彼得罗辛的儿子布兰得利
I think he's Mr. Petrosian's son Bradley.
有发现吗  里瑟先生
Any luck, Mr. Reese?
布兰得利・彼得罗辛是个好学生
Bradley Petrosian has been a good student.
没给任何人打过电话
Hasn't phoned anyone,
没跟任何可疑人物交谈过
hasn't spoken to any suspicious characters.
这么说我们找错对象了
So are we barking up the wrong tree?
有可能
Maybe.
等等
Hang on.
他正跟人见面
He's meeting someone.
芬奇...
Finch...
你说的没错  我们找错对象了
You were right about the wrong tree.
什么意思
What?
我不认为布兰德利・彼得罗辛
I don't think Bradley Petrosian
跟克劳迪娅・克鲁兹有一腿
was sleeping with Claudia Cruz.
什么意思
Sorry?
他在性趣方面另有所好
His tastes run in the other direction.
那我们应该查查他父亲  阿德南
So we should look at the father, Adnan.
我去盯住他
I'll get eyes on him.
孩子现在怎么样
How's their baby doing?
她很
She's--
里瑟  你最好过来
Reese, you better get back here.
合情合理  这里有很多蜡烛
Makes sense. Lots of candles.
有一支弄到了呢绒上
One catches the drapes.
知道为什么克劳迪娅没逃走吗
Do we know why Claudia didn't run?
血液检查有酒精残余
Blood screen showed traces of alcohol.
这么说她喝醉了  睡着了
So she was drinking. She fell asleep.
烟雾警报器失效了
Faulty smoke alarm.
消防局长说电池没电了
Fire Marshal said the battery was dead.
问题不是电池  是电线
Battery isn't the problem. Wiring is.
电线上只剩下一层塑料涂料
The hot wire is just plastic coating.
里边的电线被拿走了
The wire itself was removed.
没有线路连接  所以没有报警
No connection, no alarm.
如果是电池没电  就是意外  但这个
Dead battery could be an accident, but this--
你有验尸的照片吗
You got the autopsy photos?
有
Yeah.
法医说裂口是高温造成的  不是外伤
ME said heat caused the cracks, not trauma.
高温的确能导致头骨裂开
High temperatures can cause the skull to fissure.
裂口沿着骨头缝裂开的
Cracks all along the plate lines of the skull.
头骨上没有自然形成的缝  但是
There is no natural plate line there, but--
-这是因为殴打造成的  -没错
- It was caused by a blow. - Yeah.
着火的时候她已经昏迷了
She was unconscious when the fire was set.
用什么打的
But a blow with what?
骨头裂开了
Bone was cracked.
但是没有穿透  也没有粉碎
Wasn't pierced or shattered.
是圆的东西
Something round.
比如这个
Like this?
有可能
Could be.
把烟灰弄掉后  可能会有发现
You wash the soot off that, you might get lucky.
高温能够将附着的指纹刻在金属上
Heat can etch fingerprints into the metal.
或许能告诉你谁是凶手
Could give you your killer.
-你怎会把她弄丢呢  -我没有
- But how could you let her go? - I didn't.
她撞倒了书本  自己走开了
She just knocked down the books and walked off.
她不会走路  芬奇
She can't walk, Finch.
上帝
God.
我永远不会原谅自己
I'll never forgive myself.
快交给我  莉拉
Give it to me now, Leila.
-拜托交给我  -你找到她了
- Please just give it to me. - You got her?
上帝  那是个手榴弹
My God, that's a grenade.
拜托快点
Please just--
只是个催泪弹
Just a tear gas grenade.
还是个手榴弹
It's still a grenade.
没事的  没事的  小宝贝
You're okay. You're okay, sweetie.
过来  没事的
Come on. It's okay.
我早叫你把武器搬走
I told you to move your arsenal.
-我准备搬了  -什么时候
- I was going to. - When?
等这里被炸平后吗
After the whole place is blown up?
你知道我不喜欢枪
You know how I feel about guns.
总这样不行
This really isn't working,
我们俩总得留下一人  专门照顾她
one of us always being here, minding the baby.
是你把她偷过来的
Well, you're the one who stole her.
多谢提醒
Thanks for reminding me of that.
我要把她送到她外祖父母那里去
I'm gonna take her to her grandparents.
在我们扫除威胁照看她
They can keep an eye on her until we neutralize the threat.
芬奇  坏人找上了克劳迪娅
Finch, the bad guys got to Claudia.
叔叔抱
Here we go.
他们也可能找上萨米和韦达
They could be after Sammy and Veda too.
所以我已经把他们转移到安全屋了
That's why I've already moved them to a safe house.
怎么  撇开我自己查案了
What, are you working a case without me?
只是一起意外死亡  有可能转为
Just an accidental death, which might turn out
-定性成凶案  -是谁
- to be a homicide. - Who is it?
一个叫克劳迪娅・克鲁兹的姑娘
A girl named Claudia Cruz.
我刚从犯罪现场回来
Just left the crime scene.
可能发现了凶器
Might have found the murder weapon.
舍曼斯基
Szymanski.
真是抱歉  我刚才有点事
I am so sorry. I got caught up.
我会尽快赶到的
I'll be there as soon as possible.
我能帮什么忙吗
Anything I can do to help?
能帮我把这些送去罪证化验室吗
Think you could take these down to the Crime Lab for me,
叫他们马上处理
ask them to put a rush on it?
没问题
Yeah, sure.
-多谢了  -只有这些吗
- Thanks. - But is that it?
舍曼斯基不是集团犯罪科的吗
Szymanski-- Isn't he Organized Crime?
卡特  你清楚我是你的人  对吧
Carter, you know I got your back, right?
舍曼斯基约我出去
Szymanski asked me out on a date.
拜托别跟别人乱说  好吗
Can you not spread it around, please?
我尽量
I'll try not to.
你接着做事
Look, why don't you go ahead
我把这个送去化验室  好吧
and I'll run this down to the lab, all right?
谢了  莱奈尔
Thanks, Lionel.
欠你一回
I owe you.
我去检查一下是否安全
I'll check if it's clear.
芬奇
Finch!
查到什么了
What did you get?
他们车上有全球定位追踪器
There was a GPS tracker on their car.
这不是你们的错
It's not your fault.
很抱歉你们还未脱离险境
I'm sorry you're still in danger.
我们还得再转移你们
We have to move you again.
你们去收拾下东西好吗
Can you get your things?
如果我们今天晚上救不了莉拉
If we don't recover Leila tonight,
她会被送离这个国家
she'll be out of the country.
永远消失
Gone for good.
知道这些人的来历吗
Any idea who those men were?
不是阿尔巴尼亚人就是克罗地亚人
They're Albanians or Croats.
也许是某个东欧犯罪集团
Probably one of the Eastern European crime groups.
你准备怎么做
What are you gonna do?
不惜一切代价
Whatever I have to.
为什么我看到的
How come I only ever see
不是你就是舍曼斯基
you or Szymanski?
如果以利亚至关重要
If this Elias is such a big deal,
纽约警局的其他人上哪儿去了
where's the rest of the NYPD?
你记性真差啊  吉亚尼
You got a bad memory, Gianni.
以利亚极力想做掉你
Elias just tried to kill you.
越多警察知道你在这儿
The more cops know you're here,
他能找到你的可能性就越大
the more chance of him finding you.
为了你自己好  先帮我们找到他
So for your own sake, help us find him first.
卡特
Carter.
卡特  我刚从化验室出来
Hey, Carter, yeah, I was in the Crime Lab.
他们说你给了他们个紧急任务
They said they had a rush job for you
查卡劳迪娅・克鲁兹案里的一个凶器
on some murder weapon in a Claudia Cruz case.
有发现吗
They get anything?
他们找到了配对  凶手有案底
Yep, they got a match. Your killer was in the system,
多亏十年前的一起公路纠纷事件
thanks to a road rage incident about ten years ago.
是谁
What's the name?
你是谁  你在干...
Who are you? What do you--
保安
Security!
-她在哪儿  -什么  谁
- Where is she? - What? Who?
这东西的所有人绑架了莉拉
The owner of this kidnapped Leila.
告诉我他把莉拉带哪儿去了
Tell me where he's taken her.
我不知道  我向上帝发誓我不知道
I don't know. I swear to God I don't.
你和克劳迪娅・克鲁兹有外遇  不是吗
You had an affair with Claudia Cruz, didn't you?
好吧  是的
Okay. Yes.
你杀了克劳迪娅
You had Claudia killed
-绑架了她的宝宝  -没有
- and the baby kidnapped. - No.
我不可能干出那种事
I would never do anything like that.
你想怎样  严刑逼供吗
What are you gonna do, torture him?
你已经触发了无声警报
You've tripped the silent alarm.
卡特
谋杀克劳迪娅的凶手找到了
凶器上有妻子的指纹
警察会在五分钟内赶到
The police are gonna be here in five minutes.
我不会对他严刑逼供的
I'm not gonna torture him
因为是你的指纹印在
because your fingerprints are on the weapon
杀害克劳迪娅的凶器上
that killed Claudia.
-尼可娜  你做了什么  -闭嘴
- Nicola, what did you do? - Shut up.
是你雇人抢走了莉拉  是不是
Did you hire the men that took Leila? Did you?
没错
Yes.
-给他们打电话  -我做不到
- Call them. - I can't.
号码已经停机了
The number doesn't work anymore.
-你从哪儿弄到的  -某个欧洲的家族
- Where'd you get it? - Family in Europe.
我打了电话  一个男人接的
I called it. A man answered.
我跟他说了我的麻烦
I told him the problem.
我一付完款  号码就会作废
Once I paid him, he said the number would be dead.
我联系不到他  更没法中止任务
And I couldn't contact him, not even to stop the job.
任务就是要把克劳迪娅的死亡
And the job was to make Claudia's death
伪装成意外
look like an accident,
再摆脱掉孩子
get rid of the baby.
你怎么能这么做
How could you do such a thing?
总得有人给你收拾烂摊子
Somebody had to clean up your mess.
你无能无力了  他们已经走了
And there's nothing you can do. They're gone.
我要找这个东西的所有人
I want the man that owns this.
他绑架了一个孩子
He has kidnapped a child,
一名婴儿
a baby.
我想知道他在哪儿
I want to know where he is.
玩真格的吗
Really?
再问一次
One more time.
-我怎么能找到他  -我不知道
- How do I find him? - I don't know.
我会杀了你
I will kill you.
杀了我吧  我还是不知道
So kill me, but I still don't know.
你的小宝贝已经被带走了
Your baby's gone.
抢走孩子的人肯定已经转手了
Whoever he was just handed him over.
他自己都不知道了
Even he couldn't tell you.
来啊
So go ahead.
开枪啊
Shoot.
就是说没人知道她在哪儿
So no one knows where she is.
也不是没人
Not no one.
有一个人掌控黑社会
There is someone who knows the underworld,
战士  黑帮  集团大鳄
the soldiers, the gangs, the syndicates.
拜托  你在开玩笑
Come on, you're not serious.
你还留着那个电话吧
You still have that burner phone?
不行  我们不能用那个
No, we can't use it.
莉拉在那些人手里
Leila is in the hands of men
事情有变他们会眼睛不眨地杀了她
who won't hesitate to kill her if things go bad.
这是在铤而走险
It's still too risky.
能试的我都试了  芬奇
I'm all out of moves, Finch.
剩下的也只有铤而走险了
Risk is all I've got left.
我必须打这个电话
I have to make the call.
他凭什么会同意和你见面
Why would he even agree to meet with you?
因为他会好奇
Because he'll be curious.
约翰  很高兴又见面了
John, it's good to see you again.
和我说说  是不是和你老板闹掰了
So tell me, did you fall out with your boss?
你在寻求活儿吗
Are you looking for a job?
我在寻求帮助
I'm looking for help.
我的帮助吗
From me?
我凭什么要帮你
Why would I help you?
我救过你一命
I saved your life.
确实  你救过
You did, didn't you?
但你也破坏了我计划好的
But you also broke up a little family reunion
家庭小聚
that I had planned.
是你做的  不是吗
That was you, wasn't it?
坦诚错误
Honest to a fault.
是什么事
What's this about?
有人绑架了一个孩子
Someone kidnapped a child,
杀害了她的母亲
murdered her mother.
就像莫雷蒂杀害了你的母亲
Just like Moretti murdered your mother,
夺走了你的童年
stole your childhood.
-我活了下来  -这个孩子不会
- I survived. - This child won't.
她只有六个月大
She's six months old,
一名婴儿
a baby.
我知道你想掌管这个城市
I know you're aiming to take over this city,
但要想控制它  你需要规则
but to control it, you need rules.
人们开始对孩子下手
People start targeting children,
规则就不复存在
there are no rules.
没人有好处
No winners.
谁是绑架案的幕后黑手
Who's behind the kidnapping?
东欧人
Eastern Europeans.
有人雇他们把这个孩子运出国去
They've been paid to get the baby out of the country.
他们今晚就要动手了
And they're moving her tonight.
他们的运输范围不包括新泽西南部
Their remit doesn't extend south of Jersey.
他们会把孩子交给墨西哥人
They'll hand it off to the Mexicans.
那些才是人口贩子
They're the people smugglers.
像是这样的转手交易
A hand-off like that --
你一定可以找出交易地点
you can find out where it's happening,
把我带过去
and you can get me there.
交易在卡姆登路1637号
Hand-over's at 1637 Camden.
你也许能赶上
You might get there in time.
我本来应该一枪崩了你
I would have just shot you,
但是老板却对你大发慈悲
but the boss has got a soft spot for you.
-里面没人  -在那边
- There's no one in it.  - Over there!
最后一次机会  把枪放下
Last chance. Put your weapons down
慢慢走开
and walk away.
好吧  好吧  都听你的伙计
Okay. All right. Whatever you say, man.
快点  走
Come on. Go.
站住  孩子在我手上  我说了  站住
Stop, I have the baby. I said, "Stop."
把包放下
Put the bag down.
不要
No.
你有种就开枪
You'd just shoot me.
没错
You're right.
没事的  莉拉  没事了
It's okay, Leila. You're okay.
你安全了
I got you.
芬奇  莉拉在我这了
Finch, I've got Leila.
我现在带她回去
I'm bringing her back.
她没事
She's okay.
一会儿见
Won't be long, huh?
好了
Okay.
抱歉  老板改变主意了
Sorry. Boss had a change of heart.
约翰
John?
你对那个孩子做了什么
What have you done with the baby?
她就在这  约翰
She's right here, John.
咱们有言在先的
We had an agreement.
但是后来我发现有件事
But then I realized there is something
你能帮上忙
you can do for me.
告诉我莫雷蒂在哪儿
Tell me where Moretti is.
我不知道
I don't know.
这是个冰柜车  约翰
This is a refrigerated truck, John.
里面的温度会急速下降
It will get very cold in there very quickly.
我猜你也许能撑上几个小时
You'll be able to hold off for a few hours, I imagine.
但是  这个小家伙可就
But this little one, on the other hand --
以利亚
Elias.
你要是改变主意了就喊
Just shout if you change your mind.
别这样
Don't do this.
以利亚  以利亚
Elias. Elias!
卡特那边有情况吗
Anything on Carter yet?
我跟踪了她
I followed her.
有所发现
Learned something.
什么
What?
你发现了什么
What'd you learn?
她
She...
她吃了个披萨
She had a pizza.
她超喜欢意大利辣香肠
She got a thing for pepperoni.
而我手上有你犯下的命案
And I got a dead body with your name on it.
别以为我不会善加利用
Don't think I won't use it.
去查查她把莫雷蒂藏在哪了
Find out where she's got Moretti.
坚持住  莉拉
Just hold on, Leila.
拜托
Please.
弗斯科
Hey, Fusco.
-什么事  -检验结果出来了
- Yeah?  - Crime lab came through.
想不想去惹惹杀害克劳迪娅・克鲁兹的凶手
Wanna go harass Claudia Cruz's murderer?
好呀  何乐而不为呢
Yeah, sure, why not?
稍等  我要接个电话
One second. I got to take this.
-我是卡特  -警探
- Carter.  - Detective.
约翰救回了孩子  但我跟他失去联系了
John recovered the baby, but then I lost him.
失去联系了  那孩子呢
Lost him? And the baby?
最后的信号是在布鲁克林卡姆登街1637号
Last-known location, 1637 Camden in Brooklyn.
尽你所能吧警探  拜托了
Anything you can do, Detective, please.
好的
Okay.
抱歉  莱奈尔  我突然有点事
Sorry, Lionel, something's come up.
凶手名叫尼可娜・彼得罗辛  你自己去吧
Nicola Petrosian. She's all yours.
过来  来
Come here. Come on.
来  宝贝
Come on, baby.
来
Come on.
以利亚  以利亚
Elias. Elias.
什么事  约翰
Yes, John?
好吧
All right.
你赢了
You win.
我们双赢  约翰
We both win, John.
莫雷蒂在哪
Where's Moretti?
我凭什么相信你会守信
What guarantee do I have?
你别无选择
You don't.
皇后区杰弗逊大街1465号
1465 Jefferson...Queens.
谢谢你  约翰
Thank you, John.
你说的没错  我不会伤害孩子
You were right. I would never harm a child.
但我知道你也不会
But then I knew you wouldn't either.
再见  约翰
Good-bye, John.
以利亚  以利亚
Elias! Elias!
坚持住  坚持住  宝贝儿
Come on. Come on, baby.
坚持住  宝贝儿
Come on, baby.
哭啊  哭啊
Cry. Cry.
莉拉在卡车里  我得开你的车走
Leila's in the truck. I got to take your car.
-到底发生了什么事  -是以利亚
- What on earth happened?  - Elias happened.
卡特
Carter.
以利亚知道莫雷蒂的所在地了
Elias knows where Moretti is.
他是怎么知道的
How does he know?
我在路上了  你赶紧过去
I'm on my way. Just get over there.
舍曼斯基  我是卡特  咱们暴露了
Szymanski, Carter, we've been blown.
赶紧把莫雷蒂带走
Get Moretti out of there now.
吉亚尼  我是舍曼斯基
Gianni! It's Szymanski.
吉亚尼
Gianni.
正好跟我喝一杯
Just in time for a drink.
恐怕不行  卡特说我们得马上转移
Afraid not. Carter says we got to move.
快点  拿上你的东西
Quick. Get your stuff.
听得到吗  里瑟先生
Are you there, Mr. Reese?
我在  卡特也在
I'm here. So is Carter.
不
No.
派辆车到皇后区杰弗逊大街1465号
I need a bus. 1465 Jefferson, Queens.
一位警官腹部中枪
Officer down with a gunshot to the abdomen.
重复  警官受伤
I repeat, officer down.
莫雷蒂
Moretti.
他们把他抓走了
They got him.
以利亚怎么会知道
How did Elias know?
是我告诉他的
I told him.
为了救孩子我只能把安全屋的地址给他
I had to give up the safe house to save the baby.
约翰  你为什么要和以利亚说呢
John, why were you even talking to Elias?
我别无选择
I had no choice.
我们把孩子丢了
We lost the kid.
你说你别无选择  可其实你有  约翰
You say there was no choice, but there was, John.
那就是报警
It's called the police.
那是我们的工作
It's what we do.
我不能再这样下去了
I can't do this anymore.
我做不到
I can't.
你和你的朋友
You and your friend.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
走吧
Go on.
这个地方马上就会全是警察了
This place will be swarming.
走呀
Go.
快走
Go!
再见  莉拉
Bye, Leila.
你要乖乖的哦
You be a good girl.
太感谢你们了
Thank you so much.
有一个孩子真好
Be nice to have a child.
一群孩子
Children.
我们会有那么一天吗
Think that'll ever happen?
也许不会吧
Probably not.
我们的工作
Our line of work.
有孩子的麻烦在于
The trouble with children--
你不知道孩子长大后会变成什么样的人
you never know how they're gonna turn out.
你好  爸爸
Hello, dad.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第17集
Person of Interest S01E17 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-